<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hexo on Loving life and dreams.</title><link>/en/tags/hexo/</link><description>Recent content in Hexo on Loving life and dreams.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 15:40:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/tags/hexo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Use Github, Travis CI to automatically deploy HexoCoding to OSChina Server</title><link>/en/2017/08/19/use-travis-ci-push-hexo-blog.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 15:40:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/2017/08/19/use-travis-ci-push-hexo-blog.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Usually we use &amp;lsquo;hexo deploy&amp;rsquo; locally to post blog posts to remote Pages servers, but don&amp;rsquo;t forget that we still need to submit code, so don&amp;rsquo;t feel a bit of trouble and score two steps to do it. Then it occurred to me whether the &amp;lsquo;Travis CI&amp;rsquo; tool could be used to complete the deployment? The answer is yes, and the overall process is roughly as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Edit articles locally (or on the Github website).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Submit an article to the Github server&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Travis CI receives notifications to synchronize the latest Github code and execute user-customized &amp;lsquo;Travis&amp;rsquo; scripts to generate static blogs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finally push the generated blog to the specified Pages server&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s just that one of the more troubling questions is how to protect our private keys, and if &amp;lsquo;Travis CI&amp;rsquo; is ready for us, start our journey.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rebuild your personal blog site with Hexo</title><link>/en/2017/08/02/use-hexo-rebuild-blog-site.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 16:04:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/2017/08/02/use-hexo-rebuild-blog-site.html</guid><description>&lt;p>In fact,in the &amp;lsquo;Github Page&amp;rsquo; above is also mixed for a long time, although now a variety of blog sites are emerging, but as the IT industry&amp;rsquo;sprogram apes still like to do their own trouble, success is certainly happy failure will also be inappropriate. &amp;lsquo;Github Page&amp;rsquo; was first launched using &amp;lsquo;Jekyll&amp;rsquo;, a simple explanation that is actually a static web site tool, and now there&amp;rsquo;sa tool called&amp;rsquo;Hexo'(&amp;lsquo;Nodejs&amp;rsquo;) implementation.' Both goals are the same, but by contrast, it&amp;rsquo;s reallyeasier to get started with Hexo,plus it&amp;rsquo;s easy to debug locally, so there&amp;rsquo;san idea to flip over again and build a&amp;rsquo;Hexo&amp;rsquo;version of your personal blog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introducing another static website tool, &amp;lsquo;Gor&amp;rsquo; (&lt;a href="https://github.com/wendal/gor),">https://github.com/wendal/gor),&lt;/a> it&amp;rsquo;s a masterpiece of The GreatErnest (Wendal) (&lt;a href="http://wendal.net/">http://wendal.net/&lt;/a>) that people familiar with the &amp;lsquo;GO&amp;rsquo; language have to follow.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>