<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on Loving life and dreams.</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on Loving life and dreams.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 19:04:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lisenhui.cn/en/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Install a font on linux Chinese font</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2019/10/21/install-linux-chinese-fonts.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 19:04:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2019/10/21/install-linux-chinese-fonts.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Usually rarely use the UI desktop on Linux service machines, but there is still a chance to encounter, this does not today encounter the Linux version of firefox browser display Chinese garbled code. No matter how to debug the browser&amp;rsquo;s related settings, there is no way to work together, even a little depressed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://siteimgs.lisenhui.cn/2019/10-31-firefox-browser-err01.png-alias" alt="firefox-browser-err01.png">
&lt;img src="http://siteimgs.lisenhui.cn/2019/10-31-firefox-browser-err02.png-alias" alt="firefox-browser-err02.png">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Install the pymsql module under Mac/Linux</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2017/08/16/mac-install-pymssql-module.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 13:50:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2017/08/16/mac-install-pymssql-module.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Accessing and connecting MSSQL data in a non-&amp;lsquo;Windows&amp;rsquo; environment is a hassle in itself. Since writing the &amp;lsquo;Python&amp;rsquo;program in the &amp;lsquo;ORM&amp;rsquo; aspect are the use of the&amp;rsquo;pyxxx&amp;rsquo;module, it is not true that the connectionMSSQLalso has a module called&amp;rsquo;pymsql&amp;rsquo;,but the actual use is notparticularly smooth. If the author is in the environment is so, the development environment is &amp;lsquo;OSX 10.11&amp;rsquo;, the release environment is &amp;lsquo;CentOS 6.4&amp;rsquo;, according to the official installation steps, the Linux environment is &amp;lsquo;OK&amp;rsquo;, but the Mac environment installation failure, the wrong stack information is as follows:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Supervisor introduction and use</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2017/05/18/linux-daemon-supervisor.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 07:10:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2017/05/18/linux-daemon-supervisor.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Many times our own development or other services do not have a background daemon, then the process can easily be accidentally killed, at this time need to have a program to monitor and maintain these program services. An online search revealed that the &amp;lsquo;Supervisor&amp;rsquo; component was exactly what we wanted, while also supporting the unified management of these programs, Nice!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Linux uses SSH password-free login</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2016/05/29/ssh-login-without-password.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 12:34:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2016/05/29/ssh-login-without-password.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Now distributed clusters are very popular, often switch back and forth on different machines that is common. If each switch needs to enter a username and password, that is to crash the rhythm ah. Fortunately, &amp;lsquo;SSH-KEY&amp;rsquo; gives us convenience, as long as the &amp;lsquo;master&amp;rsquo; generates a &amp;lsquo;PUB_KEY&amp;rsquo;, and then copied to &amp;lsquo;clusters&amp;rsquo;, you can use&amp;rsquo;ssh hostname' directly later to quickly and easily switch to the machine that needs to operate&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Git action command collection</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2016/01/29/git-commands-collect.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 12:34:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2016/01/29/git-commands-collect.html</guid><description>&lt;p>All say good sex is not as bad as bad writing, there is nothing wrong with it. Although learning Git has been for more than a year, but sometimes the less used commands are always a moment to remember. So decided to write it into the blog, not only to share the experience, but also easy to find their own, this blog post will continue to add up. .&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>