<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quick Start on Loving life and dreams.</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/docs/quickstart/</link><description>Recent content in Quick Start on Loving life and dreams.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 12:04:23 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lisenhui.cn/en/docs/quickstart/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Upgrade</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/docs/quickstart/upgrade.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 16:01:08 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/docs/quickstart/upgrade.html</guid><description>Next theme is still being updated. You are welcome to follow the following two warehouse addresses. You can click follow to get the update notice of the theme.
Github: elkan1788/hugo-theme-next Gitee: lisenhui/hugo-theme-next Git pull Switch to the root directory of the NexT theme, such as cd themes/hugo-theme-next, and execute the git pull command to pull the latest theme code.
Git submodule update Switch to the root directory of the site and execute the git submodule update --remote --merge command to pull the latest theme code.</description></item><item><title>Deployment</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/docs/quickstart/deployment.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 15:24:54 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/docs/quickstart/deployment.html</guid><description>GitHub or Gitee can support both Hugo source code and static site code.
##Hugo source code
###GitHub operation
Open the GitHub repository access address of your site, and select the corresponding branch and path of the site code in the source under the settings -&amp;gt; pages path to take effect.
###Gitee operation
Open the Gitee repository access address of your site, select the corresponding location of the site in the deployment branch and deployment directory under the path of service -&amp;gt; gitee pages, and click the Publish button to take effect.</description></item><item><title>Configuration</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/docs/quickstart/configuration.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 15:04:33 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/docs/quickstart/configuration.html</guid><description>NexT theme uses modular configuration files by default, and the directory structure is as follows:
config `-- _default |-- config.toml |-- languages.toml |-- menu.toml |-- params.toml `-- params.zh-CN.toml config.toml： Hugo global settings languages.toml： Multilingual settings menu.toml： Site&amp;rsquo;s menu settings params.toml： Common third party settings params.zh-CN.toml： Parameter configuration of Chinese website In the process of local development (writing articles), in order to facilitate debugging or ensure that some account information is not leaked, you can create a development (customizable name) folder under the config directory to use and configuration file with the same name under the _default folder files to overwrite the default configuration information.</description></item><item><title>Installation</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/docs/quickstart/installation.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 14:14:53 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/docs/quickstart/installation.html</guid><description>There were provides template and Git submodule two ways for install NexT theme, which can be selected according to your own situation.
Template Applicable to the case of setting up a personal site for the first time. Login github website with your account then visit NexT Starter , click the green button which name is Use this template and fill in your site name and description, after click bottom button with name Create repository from template that will automatically generate your own site code.</description></item></channel></rss>