<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>KindEditor on Loving life and dreams.</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/categories/kindeditor/</link><description>Recent content in KindEditor on Loving life and dreams.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2011 22:10:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lisenhui.cn/en/categories/kindeditor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>JSP version of KindEidtor Online Editor Season 2 - Servlet and Struts2 Integrated Edition</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2011/10/17/kindeditor-jsp-struts2-servlet.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2011 22:10:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2011/10/17/kindeditor-jsp-struts2-servlet.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Some time ago, I posted a post on the forum entitled &amp;ldquo;JSP Edition&amp;rsquo;s Complete KindEditor Online Editor (with attachment upload and image classification management features)&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href="http://elkan1788.github.io/OnlineEditor/2011-03-24/">http://elkan1788.github.io/OnlineEditor/2011-03-24/&lt;/a>) Kindeditor-jsp-complete .html) got a positive response from everyone, but I feel a little regret, there are a lot of people are not really talking about technical issues, but to me to ask for source code, to say that the real results of their own labor so in vain dedication, feel a little sorry for themselves, to know that our domestic technicians are not backed by money ah. Alas, I&amp;rsquo;ve been too busy lately and I don&amp;rsquo;t care too much about it. After seeing so many people left a mark, feel that they should also be selfless is it, we old Mao said right: to learn like Comrade Lei Feng, ha ha &amp;hellip; In fact, above I have already said, this JAR inside the function I just put the official website JSP code adaptation only, nonsense first do not say much, the following directly on the code bar, can be secured Oh.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open JSP KindEditor's attachment JAR package source code</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2011/05/05/kindeditor-jsp-source.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2011 09:32:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2011/05/05/kindeditor-jsp-source.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect the response to be so strong when I wrote a JSP version of kindeditor editor in March. However, with the growth of the day and month, this version of the plug-in also exposed some BUG, such as: Struts2 how to integrate, web.xml file configuration upload properties inconvenient to modify and cumbersome, upload pictures (attachments) can not be saved in other disks &amp;hellip; &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip; 。 Now usually developed projects are using KE as an online editor, in order to be better and more convenient to use this editor, in the rest of the time to refactor the original code re-encapsulation, in addition to the previous version of the BUG, but also unified the overall naming specifications, added some new features.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>JSP's complete KindEditor online editor</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2011/03/24/kindeditor-jsp-complete.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2011 21:17:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2011/03/24/kindeditor-jsp-complete.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using FCKEditor online editors before, and of course I&amp;rsquo;ve used other online editors like eWebEditor, TinyMCE, CuteEditor,jHtmlArea, etc.,but they weren&amp;rsquo;t used when the final project was released because they were either dull, too cumbersome to configure, too few features, poor browser compatibility, and so on. Last year, a chance chance gave me an opportunity to get to know kindEditor, an online editor that, as its name says, is a friendly editor that is not only simple in size, but also quite impressive in its function and skin. There is also a very important factor, it is our people&amp;rsquo;s development of free tools, from the product release to date the pace of renewal has not stopped Oh. Here&amp;rsquo;s a look at my perfect KindEditor.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>