<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ambari on Loving life and dreams.</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/tags/ambari/</link><description>Recent content in Ambari on Loving life and dreams.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 16:13:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lisenhui.cn/en/tags/ambari/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>An issue with the service in Ambari that is functioning properly but the service stops</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2017/10/18/ambari-monitor-status-issues.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 16:13:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2017/10/18/ambari-monitor-status-issues.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Many times the maintenance of the environment is indeed a headache event, which does not originally show the monitoring of normal services on Ambari&amp;rsquo;s Dashboard page, there is a strange phenomenon: in the machine query service running process is normal, but partial Ambari&amp;rsquo;s UI interface is displayed as a stop, but the port check shows normal. Here&amp;rsquo;s the picture:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://siteimgs.cn-sh2.ufileos.com/2017/10-18-ambari-red.png" alt="alert_stopped.png">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Problems with HiveServer2 due to the JDBC version</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2017/10/17/hive2-jdbc-connector-issues.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 17:33:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2017/10/17/hive2-jdbc-connector-issues.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Previously, &amp;lsquo;HDP&amp;rsquo; was used to build and manage the &amp;lsquo;Hadoop&amp;rsquo; environment, and there were no difficult problems when the installation was debugged, but this time it was a strange problem when it was deployed on the &amp;lsquo;Centos6x&amp;rsquo; system:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the face of it, the Hive service is functioning normally, the process is running normally, the page UI is normal, and the logs are not output incorrectly. Simple table-building statements can be executed, which can be caused by throwing exceptions when importing local/HDFSdata. The wrong stack information is as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">com.mysql.jdbc.exceptions.jdbc4.MySQLSyntaxErrorException: You have an error in your SQL syntax; check the manual that corresponds to your MySQL server version for the right syntax to use near &amp;#39;OPTION SQL_SELECT_LIMIT=DEFAULT&amp;#39; at line 1
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Another problem is that the HDFS data import prompt file does not exist using the&amp;rsquo;HiveView&amp;rsquo;UI provided by Ambari,with the error message as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">org.apache.hive.service.cli.HiveSQLException: Error while compiling statement: FAILED: SemanticException Line 1:17 Invalid path &amp;#39;&amp;#39;/tmp/xxx/xxxxx.csv&amp;#39;&amp;#39;: No files matching path hdfs:/...
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>