<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Axure on Loving life and dreams.</title><link>/en/tags/axure/</link><description>Recent content in Axure on Loving life and dreams.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 10:11:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/tags/axure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Axure tutorial: Dynamic panel content is displayed beyond the bounds</title><link>/en/2018/03/12/axure-lightbox-shade.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 10:11:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/2018/03/12/axure-lightbox-shade.html</guid><description>&lt;p>The problem&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As user needs are constantly updated and product prototype designs are being upgraded iteratively, it is important to make the overall design more complex, with more factors affecting each component. This is not now encountered when a hidden component is displayed on the dynamic panel, the resulting pull-down component is not fully displayed, really good is depressed, as shown in the following image:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://myblog.lisenhui.cn/2018/03-12-axure-state-auto-display01.png-alias" alt="axure-state-auto-display01.png">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Axure tutorial: Implement table data presentation</title><link>/en/2017/12/29/axure-datalist-table.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 18:45:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/2017/12/29/axure-datalist-table.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Typically, in the system management background, it is most common to present data in the form of lists (tables). It&amp;rsquo;s not easy to implement this list of data when you&amp;rsquo;re using Axure to prototype your product, perhaps using rectangles to piece it together, or to lay it out directly using table controls. But this is not very convenient, first of all, layout trouble, second, data modification is more troublesome. Next, let&amp;rsquo;s show you how to implement a list of data using the Table plus Repeater control.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Axure Tutorial : Implementing a dynamic matte layer</title><link>/en/2017/12/15/axure-lightbox-shade.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 20:22:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/2017/12/15/axure-lightbox-shade.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Today, while doing product prototyping, I encountered a difficulty with dynamically emerging the matte layer. &amp;ldquo;Helpless&amp;rdquo; in pursuit of high fidelity effect, or spent a little effort to do a prototype to achieve. To do a good job back to see the words, in fact, the effect of the difficulty is not great, just to see whether the personal will want to do it. Axure itself provides the functionality of a template, that is, as long as it is implemented once but once and for all. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the process and effect of this mask layer.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>