<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Java on Loving life and dreams.</title><link>/en/tags/java/</link><description>Recent content in Java on Loving life and dreams.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 21:11:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/tags/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MapDB synchronous read and write example</title><link>/en/2016/01/19/mapdb-write-read-sync.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 21:11:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/2016/01/19/mapdb-write-read-sync.html</guid><description>&lt;p>MapDB is a fast, easy-to-use embedded Java database engine. One of the most important features is the support of disk storage, directly in-memory Hash Map synchronous write to disk. Another particular surprise is that it supports ACED transactions, MVCC isolation, and full-time developer support&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After reading the official documentation and examples, you can basically be sure that it meets the requirements of the business scenario. It was also found that officials were refactoring the 3.x version, but it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be released so soon. Use google to search the next use case for MapDB, not a lot. Maybe the original official documentation is complete about it, the API is not complicated, follow the official documentation to get started&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nutz source Jdoc has a garbled solution when filling in the prompt in the IDE</title><link>/en/2012/04/20/nutz-jdoc-chinese.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 19:11:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/2012/04/20/nutz-jdoc-chinese.html</guid><description>&lt;p>There was also a period of exposure to Nutz, with a constant understanding of its use, only to find that it is more powerful and the author&amp;rsquo;s design is clever, especially like its JUnit test report, and the update speed is quite fast, to the present version of 1.b.44,ssh has the function can be said to be fully equipped. The quickest way for programmers to learn a new technology is the Demo-API,both of which are essential. Nutz is doing pretty well in this regard, for example, someone in Demo has contributed the entire CMS source code (thank you very much for sharing it and learning a lot from it), and the API provides common CHM formats and JAR packages. However, this JAR API in the implementation of the application is a little bit of a problem, let&amp;rsquo;s go into more detail.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Java program and RSR232 serial communication skills</title><link>/en/2012/03/24/java-hard-rsr232.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 22:21:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/2012/03/24/java-hard-rsr232.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning about J2EE application development and never thought about writing hardware interactions with JAVA, but I just like to try something new that I haven&amp;rsquo;t come into contact with. Searched some resources on the Internet, learned that JAVA write serial communication is quite a lot, then began to prepare for the development of debugging environment. Software program development environment is not a problem, but this hardware environment is a bit difficult. Not to mention their own use of notebook where to string ah, and if you really take this string of hardware to their own will not make, then thought of the virtual machine, think this thing should also have a virtual bar, really with their own guesses as there is really this thing, by the way also downloaded a string of small assistant for debugging.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open JSP KindEditor's attachment JAR package source code</title><link>/en/2011/05/05/kindeditor-jsp-source.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2011 09:32:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/2011/05/05/kindeditor-jsp-source.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect the response to be so strong when I wrote a JSP version of kindeditor editor in March. However, with the growth of the day and month, this version of the plug-in also exposed some BUG, such as: Struts2 how to integrate, web.xml file configuration upload properties inconvenient to modify and cumbersome, upload pictures (attachments) can not be saved in other disks &amp;hellip; &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip; 。 Now usually developed projects are using KE as an online editor, in order to be better and more convenient to use this editor, in the rest of the time to refactor the original code re-encapsulation, in addition to the previous version of the BUG, but also unified the overall naming specifications, added some new features.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>