<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mac on Loving life and dreams.</title><link>/en/tags/mac/</link><description>Recent content in Mac on Loving life and dreams.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 13:50:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/tags/mac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Install the pymsql module under Mac/Linux</title><link>/en/2017/08/16/mac-install-pymssql-module.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 13:50:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/2017/08/16/mac-install-pymssql-module.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Accessing and connecting MSSQL data in a non-&amp;lsquo;Windows&amp;rsquo; environment is a hassle in itself. Since writing the &amp;lsquo;Python&amp;rsquo;program in the &amp;lsquo;ORM&amp;rsquo; aspect are the use of the&amp;rsquo;pyxxx&amp;rsquo;module, it is not true that the connectionMSSQLalso has a module called&amp;rsquo;pymsql&amp;rsquo;,but the actual use is notparticularly smooth. If the author is in the environment is so, the development environment is &amp;lsquo;OSX 10.11&amp;rsquo;, the release environment is &amp;lsquo;CentOS 6.4&amp;rsquo;, according to the official installation steps, the Linux environment is &amp;lsquo;OK&amp;rsquo;, but the Mac environment installation failure, the wrong stack information is as follows:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The gpg signature failed when publishing jar to Maven</title><link>/en/2017/05/17/maven-deploy-center-sign-failed.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 17:02:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/2017/05/17/maven-deploy-center-sign-failed.html</guid><description>&lt;p>For a long time did not maintain their own open source projects, this time in the repair bug release encountered failure, inspection found that the reason is because of gpg signature failure, no way to change mac computer some operations are not familiar with is a bit depressed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On how to share their JAR to Maven central warehouse, there are a lot of resources on the Internet, you can try it yourself, in fact, it is not difficult, there is no need to worry about English.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Share a GitBookorganized by someone else: &lt;a href="https://skyao.gitbooks.io/leaning-maven/content/public/central/">&amp;ldquo;Published to CentralWarehouse&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Github push fail：Could not resolve hostname</title><link>/en/2017/05/16/github-push-failed.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 10:21:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/2017/05/16/github-push-failed.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Usually the most commonly used git push command suddenly can not be used (error log as follows), the brain first jumped out of the idea is: Is Github again by the wall! This has happened before and requires accelerated access by specifying hosts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Error log returned after git push execution:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">ssh: Could not resolve hostname github.com:elkan1788: nodename nor servname provided, or not known
fatal: Could not read from remote repository.
Please make sure you have the correct access rights
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>