<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Useful on Loving life and dreams.</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/categories/useful/</link><description>Recent content in Useful on Loving life and dreams.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 19:11:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lisenhui.cn/en/categories/useful/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nutz source Jdoc has a garbled solution when filling in the prompt in the IDE</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2012/04/20/nutz-jdoc-chinese.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 19:11:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2012/04/20/nutz-jdoc-chinese.html</guid><description>&lt;p>There was also a period of exposure to Nutz, with a constant understanding of its use, only to find that it is more powerful and the author&amp;rsquo;s design is clever, especially like its JUnit test report, and the update speed is quite fast, to the present version of 1.b.44,ssh has the function can be said to be fully equipped. The quickest way for programmers to learn a new technology is the Demo-API,both of which are essential. Nutz is doing pretty well in this regard, for example, someone in Demo has contributed the entire CMS source code (thank you very much for sharing it and learning a lot from it), and the API provides common CHM formats and JAR packages. However, this JAR API in the implementation of the application is a little bit of a problem, let&amp;rsquo;s go into more detail.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Domestic technology power joins forces with Nutz, KindEditor, LHGDialog, My97DatePicker</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2012/01/13/nutz-ke-lhg-my97.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 10:21:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2012/01/13/nutz-ke-lhg-my97.html</guid><description>&lt;p>For a while did not pay attention to the development of domestic IT technology, a few days ago in the study of an open source technology &amp;lsquo;Nutz&amp;rsquo; in the country want to practice a hand, but for a while do not know what to write good, think for a while or choose their own &amp;ldquo;old friend&amp;rdquo; &amp;lsquo;KindEditor&amp;rsquo;. Although it dare not be said to be a thorough understanding (personal JS level is limited, oh), but at least can also be very skilled use. Official website very early launched everyone&amp;rsquo;s long-awaited &amp;lsquo;KE4&amp;rsquo;, but I did not update together, just this time to take it to experience, hip-hop. However, the thought of those &amp;lsquo;KE&amp;rsquo; application examples written earlier is monotonous, the last one is good to have &amp;lsquo;EasyUI&amp;rsquo; as the backing, but this UI framework for smaller than the hands-on project is still a bit big. So began to think about looking for other UI to see, suddenly up the previous use of the &amp;lsquo;LHGDialog&amp;rsquo; pop-up components are quite good, then went to its official website a circle. Didn&amp;rsquo;t think it was really amazing ah, &amp;lsquo;LHG&amp;rsquo; is now also updated to 4 version, that effect is really exciting. Let&amp;rsquo;s first appreciate the fruits of the labor that took more than 2 hours (now is the time for truth), ha ha&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>