<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Juqery on Loving life and dreams.</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/tags/juqery/</link><description>Recent content in Juqery on Loving life and dreams.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lisenhui.cn/en/tags/juqery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Struts2 and jQuery implementation of non - refresh paging problem</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2010/11/03/jquery-ajax-struts2.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2010/11/03/jquery-ajax-struts2.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, I am doing a non-refresh website management background, and it as my graduation design theme, but in the code implementation encountered a little problem, I would like to ask you a two.
My design idea is roughly like this: output the generated data in the background in JSON format, and write the transmitted data in the foreground with the help of jQuery&amp;rsquo;s Ajax function.
This way in the realization of data add, change, delete function will not be difficult, but in the data query will be troublesome, how to achieve the data without refreshing paging?
I checked what some people did online, but generally found that their code was a bit cumbersome and not in line with my original design.
By looking at the JQUERY API I came up with a feasible solution (now realize some function) : in the query page countless according to first create a table style, through the JQUERY CLONE can work when querying data copy this form style at the same time will pass the data fill the background and remove the line of countless according to the style of the form.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>JQuery+ strusts1.x implements Ajax login without refresh</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2010/09/05/jquery-ajax-struts1.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2010 10:11:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2010/09/05/jquery-ajax-struts1.html</guid><description>&lt;p>In today&amp;rsquo;s increasingly mature technology development, people not only pursue technological innovation and development, but also pay more attention to the convenience of interaction with users.When programmers are still confused about the issue of data refresh before and after interaction, Ajax came out, it won the majority of programmers with the advantages of convenience and quickness.After a few years of development, it has gradually become an essential tool in our development, I will talk about a Struts1 &amp;lsquo;+&amp;rsquo; Ajax login example.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>