<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SSH on Loving life and dreams.</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/tags/ssh/</link><description>Recent content in SSH on Loving life and dreams.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 11:53:34 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lisenhui.cn/en/tags/ssh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SSH login local VM slowly with Mobaxterm</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2022/04/04/sshlogin-localvm-slowly-mobaxterm.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 11:53:34 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2022/04/04/sshlogin-localvm-slowly-mobaxterm.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, there was a problem with the local virtual machine, but a new environment was rebuilt. As a result, when logging in to the terminal with mobaxterm tool, it was found that you had to wait 4 ~ 5 seconds to enter each time. The operation inspection was not very good. I don&amp;rsquo;t understand why the local environment connection is so slow, so I still have to find a way to analyze it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some netizens have similar puzzles, suggesting that it may be the reason why they need to address through DNS during SSH login. Refer to the article to find &lt;code>/etc/ssh/sshd_config&lt;/code> sets the &lt;code>UseDNS&lt;/code> configuration item to' no &amp;lsquo;, but it is found that it is closed. What causes that?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Linux uses SSH password-free login</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2016/05/29/ssh-login-without-password.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 12:34:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2016/05/29/ssh-login-without-password.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Now distributed clusters are very popular, often switch back and forth on different machines that is common. If each switch needs to enter a username and password, that is to crash the rhythm ah. Fortunately, &amp;lsquo;SSH-KEY&amp;rsquo; gives us convenience, as long as the &amp;lsquo;master&amp;rsquo; generates a &amp;lsquo;PUB_KEY&amp;rsquo;, and then copied to &amp;lsquo;clusters&amp;rsquo;, you can use&amp;rsquo;ssh hostname' directly later to quickly and easily switch to the machine that needs to operate&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>