<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Study on Loving life and dreams.</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/tags/study/</link><description>Recent content in Study on Loving life and dreams.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 16:04:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lisenhui.cn/en/tags/study/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rebuild your personal blog site with Hexo</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2017/08/02/use-hexo-rebuild-blog-site.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 16:04:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2017/08/02/use-hexo-rebuild-blog-site.html</guid><description>&lt;p>In fact,in the &amp;lsquo;Github Page&amp;rsquo; above is also mixed for a long time, although now a variety of blog sites are emerging, but as the IT industry&amp;rsquo;sprogram apes still like to do their own trouble, success is certainly happy failure will also be inappropriate. &amp;lsquo;Github Page&amp;rsquo; was first launched using &amp;lsquo;Jekyll&amp;rsquo;, a simple explanation that is actually a static web site tool, and now there&amp;rsquo;sa tool called&amp;rsquo;Hexo'(&amp;lsquo;Nodejs&amp;rsquo;) implementation.' Both goals are the same, but by contrast, it&amp;rsquo;s reallyeasier to get started with Hexo,plus it&amp;rsquo;s easy to debug locally, so there&amp;rsquo;san idea to flip over again and build a&amp;rsquo;Hexo&amp;rsquo;version of your personal blog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introducing another static website tool, &amp;lsquo;Gor&amp;rsquo; (&lt;a href="https://github.com/wendal/gor),">https://github.com/wendal/gor),&lt;/a> it&amp;rsquo;s a masterpiece of The GreatErnest (Wendal) (&lt;a href="http://wendal.net/">http://wendal.net/&lt;/a>) that people familiar with the &amp;lsquo;GO&amp;rsquo; language have to follow.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>APIDoc automatically generates interface documentation</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2017/07/18/nodejs-apidoc-generator.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 15:23:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2017/07/18/nodejs-apidoc-generator.html</guid><description>&lt;p>For the project development common front-end separation mode, the middle in the back end to complete interface development delivery docking, front-end personnel often suffer from no interface documentation will often &amp;ldquo;run away&amp;rdquo; to harass back-end personnel, it is really painful. If there is a documented description at this time it is much easier, now the back-end popular document generation weapon has &amp;lsquo;Swagger&amp;rsquo;, although it is convenient, but also has the disadvantage of writing in the background code, and start the entire background project to access. Perhaps sometimes really not convenient, in addition to the project at the beginning of the interface to do a planning can not use this method, there is no other way?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>