<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tools on Loving life and dreams.</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/categories/tools/</link><description>Recent content in Tools on Loving life and dreams.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 16:32:10 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lisenhui.cn/en/categories/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Use Sublime Text build Hugo blog environment</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2022/02/12/use-sublime-txt-build-hugo-site.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 16:32:10 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2022/02/12/use-sublime-txt-build-hugo-site.html</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time since the establishment of &lt;code>Hugo&lt;/code>, but the previous use environment is relatively &lt;strong>&lt;code>Loose&lt;/code>&lt;/strong>, For example, the &lt;code>Sublime Text&lt;/code> text tool is used to edit blog posts, and then call &lt;code>Hugo&lt;/code> through the &lt;code>CMD&lt;/code> command line tool to perform local preview, and finally&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Use the &lt;code>git extension&lt;/code> graphic tool to publish blog posts to &lt;code>GitHub pages&lt;/code> for netizens to browse.From the perspective of the whole operation process, it&amp;rsquo;s OK. It&amp;rsquo;s just that you have to switch different tool operations in the process, and you happen to see a &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/tools/editors/#sublime-Text">&lt;strong>plug-in&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> of &lt;code>Sublime Text&lt;/code> on the official website of &lt;code>Hugo&lt;/code>, so I came up with the idea of re integrating the &lt;code>Hugo&lt;/code> use environment, Haha.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sublime Text install package failure</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2022/02/08/use-sublime-txt-build-hugo-site.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 12:31:13 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2022/02/08/use-sublime-txt-build-hugo-site.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, there was something wrong with the computer previously assigned by the company, so we had to replace it with a new one, so the environment had to be built from scratch. The always used &lt;code>Sublime Text&lt;/code> is a green version. It is normal to start and edit after copying directly. However, when trying to install a new plug-in, you encounter the following problems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GitExtensions push Github failed logging</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2021/02/22/git-extensions-push-fail.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 15:42:39 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2021/02/22/git-extensions-push-fail.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="problem-description">Problem Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>555, today experienced a &amp;ldquo;pleasure&amp;rdquo; to install the latest program!!!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you used &lt;strong>GitExtensisons&lt;/strong> to push the latest written article to Github, I encountered an inexplicable error that invalidated SSH KEY authentication. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it happened: Today, when you first open Git Extensions, it&amp;rsquo;s very friendly to pop up the update prompt window, and then you click the confirmation button unconsciously. When the results are updated, an error blocking as magical as the following occurs when pushing the article to Github:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-java" data-lang="java">
FATAL ERROR&lt;span style="color:#666">:&lt;/span> No supported authentication methods &lt;span style="color:#00a000">available&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#666">(&lt;/span>server sent&lt;span style="color:#666">:&lt;/span> publickey&lt;span style="color:#666">)&lt;/span>
&lt;span style="color:#a0a000">fatal:&lt;/span> Could not read from remote repository&lt;span style="color:#666">.&lt;/span>
Please make sure you have the correct access rights
and the repository exists&lt;span style="color:#666">.&lt;/span>
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>APIDoc automatically generates interface documentation</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2017/07/18/nodejs-apidoc-generator.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 15:23:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2017/07/18/nodejs-apidoc-generator.html</guid><description>&lt;p>For the project development common front-end separation mode, the middle in the back end to complete interface development delivery docking, front-end personnel often suffer from no interface documentation will often &amp;ldquo;run away&amp;rdquo; to harass back-end personnel, it is really painful. If there is a documented description at this time it is much easier, now the back-end popular document generation weapon has &amp;lsquo;Swagger&amp;rsquo;, although it is convenient, but also has the disadvantage of writing in the background code, and start the entire background project to access. Perhaps sometimes really not convenient, in addition to the project at the beginning of the interface to do a planning can not use this method, there is no other way?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MyEclipse6.5 plus IDE Hanhua software</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2011/05/16/myeclipse-chinese-tool.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 13:28:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2011/05/16/myeclipse-chinese-tool.html</guid><description>&lt;p>There are millions of languages and words in the world, but always feel that our square Chinese characters are better looking and more meaningful. And in the field of computers have been dominated by foreign countries, so many computers are the program in English version, sometimes it is really not convenient to use, so there is a large number of Chinese version of the program, these programs have been favored by the Chinese people.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>