<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Loving life and dreams.</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/categories/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Loving life and dreams.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 10:32:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lisenhui.cn/en/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The process of optimizing the Hugo Next theme</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2020/10/02/make-next-theme-pithy.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 10:32:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2020/10/02/make-next-theme-pithy.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="1-background">1. Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After some consideration or moving your personal blog from the Hexo engine to the Hugo engine, the blog theme is still NexT. In fact, I was worried about tossing up a brand new blog theme, and then I saw the &amp;ldquo;NexT&amp;rdquo;(&lt;a href="https://github.com/xtfly/hugo-theme-next">https://github.com/xtfly/hugo-theme-next&lt;/a>) theme shared by Lanlings on Github and quotedit directly. However, after deployment, there are areas that need to be improved, and the process of retrofitting optimization is documented here. If you also like this topic, then welcome to use, also welcome to exchange feedback.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stop using the original Chinese domain name announcement</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2020/09/17/stop-use-chinese-domain-notice.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 22:42:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2020/09/17/stop-use-chinese-domain-notice.html</guid><description>&lt;p>From today, &amp;lsquo;lisenhui.cn&amp;rsquo; will be officially launched as the unique domain name for this blog space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the morning received a notification text message from the domain name service provider, suggesting that the domain name needs to be renewed. Only found that unknowingly, the original work after the registration of the first domain name, has accompanied themselves through 7 years. At that time, Chinese the domain name is more special, and then on their own name registered &amp;lsquo;李森辉.cn&amp;rsquo;sdomain name.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog Engine Migrates to Hugo Program</title><link>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2020/08/15/blog-move-2-hugo-plan.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 10:22:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lisenhui.cn/en/2020/08/15/blog-move-2-hugo-plan.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently found that their personal blog space suddenly ind accessible, after a check found that the original is the previous use of page service providers have stopped providing services. I had no choice but to relocate back to Github Pages. But that&amp;rsquo;s the development environment that&amp;rsquo;s been re-prepared for Hexo, and it&amp;rsquo;s going to take a hard time debugging to be successful. And just then on the Internet have seen Hugo static site engine article, a Go language-based development of the extremely fast framework, development environment deployment is also simple and fast. In addition, the original domain name is also about to expire, just together to organize the blog space.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>